# Khaja Minhajuddin

Flat No 201, H.No: 12-2-39/4/1, Mehdipatnam, Hyderabad-500057 minhajuddink@gmail.com, 0091-9618085910, http://minhajuddin.com

I am a passionate software developer and have been building software for more than 10 years. I have extensive experience in technologies as diverse as Data Warehousing, Real Time Vehicle Tracking to building Web applications. I have been using **Elixir/Phoenix** to build applications professionally for more than a year. And, I have built quite a few applications using **Ruby on Rails**, **Go** and other technologies. I have very good communication skills. I can translate a given problem into an elegant and usable solution. I am also a very fast learner.

#### **Technical Skills**

Elixir, Ruby, C#, Go, C, Javascript, Coffeescript, Elixir

Phoenix, Ruby on Rails, ASP.NET, ASP.NET MVC, Sinatra, Node.js

Cucumber, Capybara, Rspec

Postgresql, MySql, SQL Server, Oracle, Mongodb, Redis, Beanstalkd, Cassandra

Elm, AngularJS, Backbone.js, jQuery, Ionic, firebase, socket.io for websockets

Git, Vim, Visual Studio, Datastage

Nginx, Varnish, Unicorn, Thin, Upstart, Docker

## **Experience**

**Software Consultant** – Azri Solutions

October 2016 - Present

**Senior Software Developer** – Cosmicvent Software

December 2015 - October 2016

**Senior Software Consultant** – Deloitte

March 2015 - December 2015

**Software Developer** – Cosmicvent Software

October 2008 - March 2015

**Systems Engineer** – Tata Consultancy Services

November 2006 - October 2008

#### Education

**Bachelor of Engineering Electronics and Communication –** Osmania University

September 2002 - April 2006

### **Projects**

**GRN connect –** http://www.grnconnect.com/ October 2016 - Present, at Azri Solutions Travel/Hotel booking provider api. Built using Elixir, Phoenix, Postgresql, Redis and other technologies
Responsible for managing the master data, homogenising the master data from multiple
upstream suppliers. Reviewing the phoenix api app. Writing Elixir Plugs for various shared apps.

## **LiveForm** – https://liveformhq.com/

August 2016 - October 2016, at Cosmicvent Software Pvt Ltd

Online form endpoints for designers and developers.

Built using Rails, Postgresql, nginx, puma, sidekiq and other technologies

Responsible for the complete code, design and concept.

### **Zammu –** https://zammu.in/

August 2015 - Now, at Cosmicvent Software Pvt Ltd

Continuous Deployment and Web host for static site generators.

Built using Rails, Postgresql, **Go, Redis**, nginx, unicorn, rabbitmq and other technologies Responsible for the complete code, design and concept.

Wash Cycle Laundry - <a href="https://app.washcyclelaundry.com/">https://app.washcyclelaundry.com/</a>

December 2011 - Current, at Cosmicvent Software Pvt Ltd

The software to manage the appointments, logistics (including routing of cyclists on Google Maps), appointment tracking and management, SMS and Email notifications for pickups deliveries, Charging and Invoicing of customers using Braintree and Xero. Customer interaction tracking via Segment.io etc,.

Built using Rails, Postgresql, jQuery, **Angular.js**, **Firebase**, redis, nginx, unicorn, **Amazon Cloudfront**, Braintree, **Twilio** and other technologies

Responsible for building the initial prototype, most of the core features, Automatic Deployment setup etc,.

**Notable Rubygems**: bootstrap-sass for twitter bootstrap integration, devise for authentication, **paper trail** for audit history of important data, **beaneater** for background processing using beanstalkd, whenever for recurring tasks, exception\_notification for error monitoring in production, **ice\_cube** for schedule storage, wicked for the signup wizard, geocoder for geocoding of customers, twilio for SMS integration, braintree for credit card processing, madmimi for email delivery, firebase for realtime notifications, sextant for route debugging in development, handlebars for client side templating, carrierwave for file uploads, activemodel-serializers and gon for json serialization and data sharing with the js frontend, pry for debugging, **bullet** for N+1 sql query detection, **mini profiler** for production performance analysis, **rspec and capybara** for unit testing and integration testing, mixpanel for customer interaction tracking, **asset\_sync** for serving assets through cloudfront CDN.

#### Websrvr – http://www.websrvr.in/

August 2014 - December 2014, at Cosmicvent Software Pvt Ltd

A simple web host which allows you to host websites/blogs and content using Dropbox. Built using Rails, Postgresql, **Go, Redis**, nginx, unicorn, beanstalkd and other technologies Responsible for the complete code, design and concept.

### Getsimplesite.com – <a href="http://getsimplesite.com/">http://getsimplesite.com/</a>

February 2014 - August 2014, at Cosmicvent Software Pvt Ltd

A simple and flexible CMS platform which allows separation of data and design. And a powerful javascript templating engine. The Go webserver for this app serves **6.5 million requests** per month.

Built using Rails, Postgresql, **Go**, jQuery, **Redis**, nginx, unicorn and other technologies Responsible the most of the code, design and concept.

**Notable Rubygems**: bootstrap-sass for twitter bootstrap integration, devise for authentication, **beaneater** for background processing using beanstalkd, whenever for recurring tasks, exception\_notification for error monitoring in production, **rmagick** for image manipulation, carrierwave for file uploads, activemodel-serializers and gon for json serialization and data sharing with the js frontend, pry for debugging, **bullet** for N+1 sql query detection, **mini profiler** for production performance analysis, **rspec and capybara** for unit testing and integration testing, mixpanel for customer interaction tracking, **asset\_sync** for serving assets through cloudfront CDN.

### Substancehq.com - <a href="https://substancehq.com/">https://substancehq.com/</a>

March 2012 - July 2013, at Cosmicvent Software Pvt Ltd

A simple and flexible blogging cum CMS platform.

Built using Rails, Mongodb, jQuery, redis, varnish, nginx, unicorn and other technologies Responsible for building the initial prototype and working on the design, user interface and major components of the app.

### Getsimpleform.com - http://getsimpleform.com/

June 2012 - July 2012, at Cosmicvent Software Pvt Ltd

A web app which allows you to build simple web forms and allows you to integrate them in a static site seamlessly.

Built using Rails, and Postgresql

Responsible for the complete code, design and concept.

### Linktub.com - https://www.linktub.com/

June 2011 - November 2012, at Cosmicvent Software Pvt Ltd

Advertisement platform

Built using Rails, Mongodb, ¡Query and other technologies

Responsible for the architecture of the app and the initial core code of the app.

#### Activayt - http://activayt.com/

March 2013 - December 2013, at Cosmicvent Software Pvt Ltd

Workflow management application for enterprises.

Built using Rails, Postgresql, Beanstalkd, AngularJs and other technologies Responsible for building the whole app.

**TimberExpress –** https://www.timberexpress.net/

May 2012 - December 2012, at Cosmicvent Software Pvt Ltd

Application which allows loggers, owners, truckers and managers of a Logging operation to keep track of the timber costs and the split of payments across them. It also allows users to generate pre-filled tax forms.

Built using Rails, Postgresql, Backbone.js and other technologies Responsible for building the whole app.

### ADMS- <a href="http://adms.maaa.org">http://adms.maaa.org</a>

March 2011 - July 2011, at Cosmicvent Software Pvt Ltd

An app build to manage the backend for a site showcasing paintings of different artists. Built using ASP.NET MVC, SQL Server and other technologies

Responsible for the development of the whole app.

#### **CAPMEI –** <u>http://www.capmei.co.in/</u>

April 2009 - August 2009, at Cosmicvent Software Pvt Ltd

An app which allows the minority consortium in Andhra Pradesh to allot admissions to different colleges based on the students preferences and their ranks in EAMCET (A competitive exam) Built using ASP.NET MVC, SQL Server and other technologies
Responsible for the development of the whole app.

## **VAM loading process**

2007 - 2008. at TCS

An ETL process which loads the billing information of Verizon Business customers into the database after extracting, cleansing and aggregating it with the service information for various billing systems.

Built using Datastage Enterprise Edition 8.0, Oracle 9i, Unix scripting, Windows Server 2003. Responsible for the design of the whole ETL process with optimized network, database usage. Coding of the critical functionality for the process.

#### Match Engine process

2007 - 2008, at TCS

An ETL process which gets the billing information from the VAM ETL process and finds a match for the new/changed billing accounts against the existing customers in the database. This process also assigns the confidence levels based on the extent of the match found. Built using Datastage Enterprise Edition 8.0, Oracle 9i, Unix scripting, Windows Server 2003. This process involved matching approximately 30,000 records with 30 million records. Responsible for the design of the whole ETL process with optimized network, database usage. Coding of the critical functionality such as the code which does the matching against the customers.

#### **GARM (Global Access Rights Management)**

2007 - 2008, at TCS

An ETL process to load and sensitize the data in the Verizon database.

Built using Datastage Enterprise Edition 8.0, Oracle 9i, Unix scripting, Windows Server 2003. Responsible for the designing of the ETL process to minimize the network, database usage and to make the process more modular.

## **D&B Duns Sync**

2007 - 2008, at TCS

A complex ETL process which synchronizes the DUNS data (from Duns & Bradstreet) with three different applications in Verizon.

Built using datastage Enterprise Edition 8.0, Oracle 9i, Unix scripting, Windows Server 2003. Responsible for the designing of the ETL process to minimize the network, database usage and to make the process more modular.

### Miscellaneous Mass uploads

2007 - 2008, at TCS

Mass uploads are ETL processes which load huge volumes of data into the database Built using Datastage Enterprise Edition 8.0, Oracle 9i, Unix scripting, Windows Server 2003. Helped the team come up with an optimized design for the various mass uploads.

## **Open Source Projects**

**Webmonitor** – https://github.com/rawcodehg/webmonitor

A phoenix/elixir web app to monitor the uptime of your web applications.

### Proquint - https://github.com/minhajuddin/proquint

An elixir package that converts ids to proquints, Identifiers that are Readable, Spellable, and Pronounceable.

## Taskr - <a href="https://github.com/minhajuddin/taskr">https://github.com/minhajuddin/taskr</a>

Open source command line utility to manage tasks, built using Ruby.

### Readcode - https://github.com/minhajuddin/readcode

A web app which allows you to read code of any public git repos, built using Ruby

### **dipper –** <a href="https://github.com/minhajuddin/dipper">https://github.com/minhajuddin/dipper</a>

A small dependency injection package in Go

### config - https://github.com/minhajuddin/config

A simple and powerful configuration utility for Go apps which uses templates in a neat way

### sync2 - https://bitbucket.org/utils/sync2/src

A Go code throttler. A simpler version is at:

http://code.websrvr.in/2014/11/04/simple-function-throttler-in-golang/

# **gokv** – <a href="https://github.com/minhajuddin/gokv">https://github.com/minhajuddin/gokv</a>

A simple key value store written in Go

# gored - https://github.com/minhajuddin/gored

A simple redis client for Go

# **Timelogger –** <u>https://github.com/minhajuddin/timelogger</u>

A terminal timelogger similar to gtimelog with analytics

# **Simpleform –** <a href="https://github.com/minhajuddin/simpleform">https://github.com/minhajuddin/simpleform</a>

A web app written in Go which allows you to setup forms similar to google forms/wufoo

## **Screencasts**

## How to implement a basic redis client in Go

https://vimeo.com/54622804

# **Building a rails app - Documentr**

https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLkUEp7pXUEJTKZ zRUdboQZACaDMZLJHX

# How to build a simple web app in golang - Redirectapp

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AiRhWG-2nGU

### Build a screencasts site

Part 1: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KnWHPW9pSSA">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KnWHPW9pSSA</a>

Part 2: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2XHI0q6jTfU">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2XHI0q6jTfU</a>